candb.com 2019-09-30

# Privacy Policy | Cook and Becker

## Privacy Statement

The purpose of this privacy statement is to inform you on how Cook & Becker B.V. (hereafter Cook & Becker B.V., Cook and Becker or Company) collects and processes data so that privacy is maintained. Cook and Becker respects and protects privacy in accordance with the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and other applicable laws. Further explanation is given here within on what kinds of personal data Cook and Becker processes, the purpose of processing and how the Company may share personal data with third parties.

This privacy statement applies to all entities of Cook & Becker B.V. and is maintained by Cook and Becker’s Netherlands office at Lange Koestraat 41, 3511RM Utrecht, The Netherlands. This privacy statement does not address applicants and employees.

This privacy statement can change from time to time and the most current statement is regularly published on the Cook and Becker website. If Cook and Becker processes major changes to this policy the customer, supplier or business partner will be kept informed by a notification on our website.

## What data is being collected?

Cook and Becker may process the below data for the purposes as described below:

• Name, address  
• Email address, telephone number  
• Data of birth and age  
• Gender   
• Location   
• Bank account number, credit card details  
• IP address, Browser ID  
• Correspondence with Cook & Becker B.V.  
• Payment data such as transaction history  
• Technical data, such as IP address, cookies, log files.  
• Behavior on site such as what (kind of) products you look at the most and other such behavior.

This list is not exhaustive and Cook and Becker may collect and process data that is useful for its services. Not all data above is collected and processed for every customer, supplier and business partners. Often the data is limited to only a few of the above details. The data collected is dependent upon the purpose of processing.  
The Company does not collect and process sensitive data such as ethnic and racial origins, political opinions, religious beliefs, trade union memberships, physical or mental health conditions, genetic or biometric details or sexual preferences. Cook and Becker may use sensitive data such as bank account number. Also, Cook and Becker may combine received data points in order to develop a profile useful in sending personalized offers and advertisements. Cook and Becker is aware of the sensitivity and impact on individual privacy and has taken appropriate actions to handle all data carefully.

## How does Cook and Becker collect data?

Cook and Becker may collect data for the use of products and services. This data may be directly collected or from individuals or from his/her devices. For example, the Company may collect data from or about the individual through the Company’s website, social media pages, customer service email messages upon sign up for Company newsletters and personalized offers, upon purchase of Cook and Becker products or when individuals register for an account. When individuals purchase a product from Cook and Becker, the Company may collect his/her registration information, status of order and purchase history. Cook and Becker may collect information about the individual from other sources such as public databases, third party processors or social media.

**Personal data directly collected from customer, supplier and business partner.**  
Cook and Becker collects and processes personal data sourced directly from the customer, supplier or other business partners. These parties have made the choice to provide this data to Cook and Becker. For example, when parties provide email addresses in order to receive a digital receipt or to conduct business with Cook and Becker.

**Personal data not obtained directly from customer, supplier and business partner.**  
Besides the above, Cook and Becker may collect personal data from these groups, obtained via third parties, as part of the service the Company provides or in connection with legal requirements that are applicable to the Company.

List of third parties Cook and Becker share their data with are, but is not limited to:

UPC  
TNT  
Google Analytics Premium  
UPS  
FedEx  
Facebook  
DHL  
Instagram  
PostNL  
Google tag manager  
DPD  
Bizzybee  
USPS

## How does Cook and Becker use this data?

Cook and Becker mainly uses this personal data based upon a contractual obligation, legal obligation, consent or legitimate interest.

Cook and Becker will process data that is necessary for the performance of a contract with suppliers and other business partners. Cook and Becker also processes data under the lawful basis of a legal obligation. Based upon legal obligation, the Company may store specific financial data for a period of time to meet requirements set by national tax authorities. Cook and Becker may also process your data for the purpose of a legitimate business interest such as to strengthen our relationship with these parties. The Company may provide these parties with communications regarding its services that it thinks might interest the parties. The Company takes into consideration the balance between privacy impacts and the Company’s legitimate business interest. Cook and Becker may process personal data when consented to do so. For example, the Company may lawfully ask these parties for consent to set up a profile in order to send personalized offers. The Company also asks permission to place a cookie on devices in order for the Company to set up profiles and place ads. When Cook and Becker processes data based on these legal grounds, these parties have the right to object, restrict, erase, access and ask data portability.

## Why does Cook and Becker process this data?

1\. To respond to questions, when contacted;  
When an individual wants to get in contact with Cook and Becker, the Company will use this data to reply on the request or question. Cook and Becker may process your name, email address and correspondence with Cook and Becker. Cook and Becker processes this data based on the individuals consent when he/she provided the data.

2\. To complete orders and when an account is registered;  
Cook and Becker asks to fill in personal information when an individual wants to complete an order and/or registers for an account. Some of this information is required: title, first name, last name, address, email, password. The information required for a purchase is based on a contractual obligation and to inform the individual about the status of the order. In order to complete a purchase Cook and Becker may use data for processing payment, delivery, status updates and other communication such as, notification of the delivery status or sending information. Information Cook and Becker may process is name, gender, contact details, email address, purchase history, bank account details. Personal information and order history are saved on a secure server.

3\. For development and improvement of products and services;  
For the legitimate interest to develop and improve products and services, Cook and Becker may collect and process personal data. Based on analysis of customers’ behavior Cook and Becker can modify its products and services. This customer behavior is based on visitor statistics and how often visitors have clicked on website pages and the items purchased. Cook and Becker may use third parties such as google analytics to analyze the visitor behavior in order to improve its services. Cook and Becker may share personal data with third parties who provide Cook and Becker with web hosting, analysis, payments and other similar services. The personal data Cook and Becker may use are contact details, email address, payment information, correspondence and technical data from the individuals devices such as IP-address, Browser ID and the pages the individual visited on the Cook and Becker website.

4\. To comply with law and regulations;  
Cook and Becker shall comply with laws and regulations and therefore personal data could be required to comply, for example for legal obligations such as tax purposes. Personal data Cook and Becker may process are name and contact details.

5\. To deliver greater website functionality;  
Cook and Becker may process technical data if an individual uses Cook and Becker’s website. This technical data is used for managing and improving the websites. If an individual chooses to enter location and preferences the Company processes this data in order to save this for the next visit. Cook and Becker uses cookies on their website in order to make sure a visit is easy to access and use. Read more about cookies in the cookie policy. Cook and Becker may process the data that is entered by the individual on our website which is linked to IP address and Browser ID.

6\. To connect with parties through social media;  
Cook and Becker makes use of social media accounts such as LinkedIn, Instagram and Facebook. The Company processes data based on consent. If an individual contacts Cook and Becker through one of the mediums the data is used in order to reply on these messages. If an individual connects through a social media account with Cook and Becker, the Company may share data with the provider of this account. The information Cook and Becker shares is governed by the social media provider Privacy Policy. Personal data Cook and Becker may process are name and email address and the data used in your message. If an individual clicks on one of the icons on the website the individual will be linked through to these third party website. If an individual enters these websites these third parties may be able to place a cookie on the same device. Read more about cookies in the cookie policy.

7\. For assessment or acceptance of customers, suppliers and other business partners;  
When a customer orders at or supplier or business partner works with Cook and Becker, the Company may process personal data to assess the identity and screening based on a contractual obligation. Cook and Becker may process contact details, name, address, email address and bank account information.

8\. For executing (contractual) agreements;  
Cook and Becker may process data when a customer purchases items on the website. The data Cook and Becker processes is based on the transaction such as name, shipping information, bank account details, consent for personalized offers and terms and conditions. Cook and Becker works with suppliers and other business partners wherefore the Company processes data for invoices, payment information and delivery information. Cook and Becker processes data such as name, address, email address, telephone number, order history and bank account number. Cook and Becker processes this data based on a performance of a contract.

9\. To show personalized advertisements;  
Cook and Becker may send personalized offers if the individual has given consent. An individual can sign up for the Cook and Becker newsletter and personalized offers by submitting an e-mail address in the newsletter module found at almost any page on this site. Cook and Becker does not send newsletters and personalized offers to customers or registered visitors unless the individual has given consent for the newsletter. All newsletters and personalized offers contain an opt-out link in case the individual wishes to unsubscribe from receiving further newsletters and personalized offers at any time. Personalized offers are send to an email address which could contain advertisements that might interest the individual based on purchase history and online behavior such as an abandoned shopping cart.

Personal data Cook and Becker process for sending out personalized offers are data the individuals shared actively with Cook and Becker such as name, email address and purchase history and data Cook and Becker obtained based on the individuals interaction with the website. Cook and Becker may use IP address and Browser ID to track your behavior on our website if you have given consent for accepting cookies.

If an individual does not want to receive these emails anymore the individual is able to withdraw consent at any time or able to unsubscribe from these newsletters and personalized offers via marketing email received.

## To whom does Cook and Becker share personal data?

Cook and Becker is a global organization and may provide data to other Cook and Becker stores and offices as this is necessary for the service it offers. This data is processed for administrative purposes. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided that information. When Cook and Becker transfers information from or about its or its use of products to other countries, the Company will protect it as described in this privacy policy. By using products parties give consent to the transfer of information from or about the individual or use of Cook and Beckers’ products to countries outside of country of residence.

Cook and Becker may process data to other companies outside of the European Economic Area. If Cook and Becker processes data with a country that does not ensure an adequate level of protection of data, Cook and Becker ensures appropriate safeguards are in place such as standard contractual clauses from the European Commission or the US Privacy Shield.

Cook and Becker has data processing agreements with third parties to ensure that data is applied with the same level of security and confidentiality as by Cook and Becker. Cook and Becker has data processing agreements with third parties which defines the rights and obligations regarding GDPR. Cook and Becker decides for which purposes the third party can process data and the third party is obliged to comply with these instructions from Cook and Becker.

## How long does Cook and Becker store your data?

Cook and Becker shall store data no longer than necessary. Cook and Becker will only store the data in line with legal retention periods and based on lawfulness of processing.

Cook and Becker may store personal data to fulfil the legal grounds of a contractual obligation, legal obligation and to prepare, defense or exercise legal claims and in general where Cook and Becker has a legitimate interest to doing so. Cook and Becker may also store data which is given through consent.

## What are your rights?

The individual has the ability to request access, restriction, portability, erasure, rectification and file a complaint by contacting Cook and Becker via the contact form at https://www.cookandbecker.com

If the individual would like to file a complaint, the Company asks that the employee sends an email via the contact form at https://www.cookandbecker.com. Please note that you can file a complaint at the Dutch Authority.

The individual has the following rights:  
• Right to access the personal data Cook and Becker holds at any time.  
• Right to ask Cook and Becker to correct his or her personal data that is incorrect and to complete incomplete information Cook and Becker holds about he or she.  
• Right to be forgotten and to object and ask Cook and Becker to delete personal data if Cook and Becker has no legal or regulatory obligation to keep this data.  
• Right to restrict personal data.   
• Right to ask Cook and Becker to provide the employee with a copy of his/her personal data that Cook and Becker holds.   
• Right to file a complaint with Cook and Becker or with the Supervisory Authority.

Cook and Becker shall communicate rectification or erasure of your personal data with third parties unless it proves impossible or involve disproportionate effort. Cook and Becker shall inform the individual of the third parties should this matter occur.

When the individual exercises a request please elaborate on the personal data Cook and Becker may process about you by giving Cook and Becker more background of the personal data. For restriction specify the request to a specific department, process, team, incident or service. Try to include timeframes, names, dates, type of processing and documents to enable Cook and Becker to process the request as soon as possible. Cook and Becker will respond to the request within one month of receipt.

## Cookies, Profiling and Withdraw Consent

Cook and Becker may send personalized offers based on account and/or website behavior. Cook and Becker only sends out personalized offers if its consented to receive these offers.

Cook and Becker uses cookies on its website such as functional, analytical and tracking cookies. Cook and Becker uses these cookies to make the shopping experience more personal. Cook and Becker shall only place a tracking cookie if explicit consent is given on the website. Cook and Becker and third parties are then able to monitor its behavior and can modify advertisements based on interests.

Parties have the right to withdraw consent at any time to unsubscribe from personalized offers via marketing emails. To withdraw consent for tracking and other cookies can be done in the cookie banner. Under ‘preferences’ the cookie settings can be adjusted.

## How do we protect your personal data?

Cook and Becker has taken appropriate and reasonable organizational and technical security measures in order to ensure the safety of your personal data in its systems. Cook and Becker shall not process data to third parties unless the Company has a legal ground to do so, for example consent is given or if it is required by law.

Additionally, employees at Cook and Becker are trained to ensure they handle all personal data with care and strict confidentiality. For staff, personnel access rights have been specified to serve the applicable legitimate purposes required for the individual to perform his or her duties.

## Links and Contact Details

Cook and Becker is not responsible for collection and processing of other organizations. This Privacy statement does not address personal data of any third party operating that is linked to Cook and Becker.

For questions or a request please contact customer service via the contact form at https://www.cookandbecker.com
